<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aneurist on Martin Koehler</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/aneurist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aneurist on Martin Koehler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Martin Koehler</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/aneurist/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>@neuInfo: accessing heterogeneous data through semantic annotation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/software/aneuinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/software/aneuinfo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@neurIST</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/aneurist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/project/aneurist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;@neurIST- Integrated Biomedical Informatics for the Management of Cerebral Aneurysms - is a European initiative within the Sixth Framework Programme Priority 2 of the Information Society Technologies IST. This 4-year project started in January 1st 2006 and finished the 31st of March 2010 with a 17 million € budget, gathering 28 public and private institutions of 12 European countries. Several organizations from the U.S.A., New Zealand and Japan participate as external collaborators. @neurIST partners include industrial, medical and academic institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@neurIST is focussed on cerebral aneurysms and provides an integrated decision support system to assess the risk of aneurysm rupture in patients and to optimize their treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@neurIST believes that the current process of cerebral aneurysm diagnosis, treatment planning and treatment development is highly compromised by the fragmentation of relevant data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@neurIST presents a new paradigm to understand and manage cerebral aneurysms. A complete IT infrastructure has been developeded for the management and processing of the vast amount of heterogeneous data acquired during diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@neurIST benefits patients with better diagnostics, prevention and treatment because it combines efforts of clinicians and industry. Through research clinicians gain a greater insight in aneurysm understanding, while industry will be dragged by these achievements to develop more suitable medical devices to treat the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
